Eoin Shanaghy: S3 has got to be the most commonly used and
most loved AWS service.
It's simple to get started with, largely cost
effective compared to alternatives,
and scales massively.
But it's not a file system.
It follows a key value object store model,
and this makes it a bit of a misfit in
cases when you want to use it like a standard
folder using regular file operations.
Now, normal file systems are usually required
for things like databases, applications that
write append log files, web applications or CMS
apps that assume a mounted folder for their
data.
And even though S3 is well supported for things
like big data and batch processing workloads,
it can actually become a performance bottleneck
if you've got lots of tiny files.
Now AWS has just released S3 files.
This is a new managed file system backed by S3.
S3 files tries to be the sweet spot,
giving you a proper file system with S3
underneath.
The promise of it is that you'll get the
scalability, durability and cost benefits of S3
with performance and behavior of a file system.
And one of the big benefits is that it
integrates easily into EC2, ECS, and even
Lambda, unlike some of the previous options.
We're going to dive very deep into S3 files,
talk you through how to use it,
where it fits, and how it compares against all
your file storage options.
You'll hear us share our experience,
since we have also been using S3 files in
real-world projects, and we also did some
benchmarking.
I'm Eoin, I'm here with Luciano.
Welcome to AWS Bites, episode 154.
Luciano, maybe you can start off by telling
everyone why is S3 not a file system in brief?
Luciano Mammino: Yeah, the first reason is because it doesn't
have the concept of directories.
What looks like a folder is basically just a key
prefix.
You can use the familiar slash to make it look
like there are directories, but it's just naming
conventions.
And in that sense, it doesn't have true
directories.
You cannot do things like atomic moves or
renames.
For instance, if you just want to rename a file
or move it from one place to another,
which basically means change the prefix
entirely,
you have to effectively, even if you use the AWS
S3 MV command, you are effectively copying the
object from one place to another.
And if you ever done that with a very large
file, a very large object on S3,
you might have noticed that it takes some time.
While if you do that in a real file system,
it's pretty much instantaneous because it's just
literally renaming the file itself and not
moving data or copying data.
So that's another big difference, which is
interesting.
The other thing is that objects are immutable.
You cannot modify a range of bytes inside an
object like you could do in a file system.
And in that sense, you cannot really append
either into an existing object.
There is a little bit of an exception,
which is multi-part uploads.
But it doesn't really work in the way you might
expect from a regular file system.
And if you want to deep dive into the details,
we have been talking about that in episode 124.
So go and check that out if you're curious.
Another thing is that listing of either the
entire bucket or a prefix can be expensive,
or at least more expensive than a regular file
system.
And this is because there is no directory
metadata in the same way that it would exist in
a file system.
So when you're running a list object operation,
it's effectively querying over the keys in the
bucket.
Access control is something that exists in S3
buckets, but again, different from what you
would have in a POSIX file system,
for example, because you can generally determine
access control using IAM policies or ACLs.
and not by setting up, I don't know,
users and groups as you would do in a POSIX
file system.
And performance is also a little bit different
because it's defined by how you structure your
partitions by using prefixes.
So if you put lots of objects in the same
prefix, you can damage your performance.
So it's typical to distribute your data over
different partitions by using a bunch of
different sub-prefixes, which makes querying S3
faster.
So specific tricks you will do with S3 that are
not necessarily mapping to things you would do
with a regular file system.
And of course, there are a lot more subtle
differences.
And the real issue here is that there are
applications out there that need file system
semantics.
So when you try to use S3,
and mimic a file system, sometimes you might
bump into things that don't necessarily match
the abstraction that the application expects.
So that's something to be aware.
And we'll see today how S3 Files tries to fill
that gap.
But I guess before getting into S3 Files,
which is pretty new, this is a topic that people
have been trying to address for a long time.
So what are the other solutions that existed for
longer than S3 Files at least?
Eoin Shanaghy: Well, you have the FUSE user space file system
option, which supports lots of file systems,
but there's an S3FS FUSE library, which allows
you to do that.
A lot of people would do that in development,
just to be able to explore buckets in a file
system.
There's also the very popular Python FS spec
S3FS library.
It's a different S3FS, which is used in a lot
of big data applications.
You also have Hadoop, has S3A, which is like a
HDFS abstraction on top of S3.
And more recently, in the last couple of years,
you have MountPoint for S3, which is Amazon's
own file system adapter.
We did a whole episode on this,
actually episode 95.
In fact, this episode covers a lot of the
options out there for mounting S3 as a file
system.
at least before S3 files came along.
Now on top of that, there are actually a whole
lot of AWS services that provide a bridge layer
between S3 and file systems, like FSX for
Lustre.
Now this is a file system for really high
performance computing with S3 as a backing data
repo.
If you're in the HPC space, that's one you'll
come across quite frequently.
There's Amazon File Cache.
This is one that never really made it
mainstream, I feel, but it's also a high
performance option.
It's a general caching layer for EC2 only that
works on top of S3 or can work on top
of NFS.
And it's built on top of Lustre,
which is one of those high performance file
systems.
The other one I can think of is Storage Gateway,
which is this whole suite of services mostly for
connecting on-premises storage to AWS.
One of those is called S3 File Gateway,
and it can present S3 as an NFS or an
SMB file share.
Now, we've covered that all in a previous
episode, episode 95, so let's get straight into
S3 files.
How does it work?
Luciano Mammino: Yeah, what we mentioned already is that S3 Files
makes a normal S3 bucket accessible as a shared
file system.
So you can still use the S3 bucket as normal,
but you can also mount it as a file system.
Any change you make in the file system is
eventually reflected in the S3 bucket.
And you can access S3 files from a bunch of
different services in AWS, like EC2,
ECS, EKS, and even Lambda using NFS.
So data isn't just stored in the bucket itself,
but you are effectively seeing it in those
compute layers as if it was a file system,
not normally available in those compute
instances.
The interesting thing is that the way the
connection with S3 is managed by S3 files,
because files can be streamed from S3 to NFS
mount, but in some cases, the files can also be
cached.
And this is by default the case for smaller
files.
So the idea is that the first time you are
accessing that file through the file system
mount, the file is going to be streamed,
but also cached in an intermediate layer,
which is going to give you increased throughput
and lower latency.
So effectively, the next time you're going to
try to access that same file, the read is going
to be much faster and you will have a much
higher throughput.
And this is something you need to be aware
because it's one of those things you can
configure for performance.
So it really depends on your use cases,
the size of the files you are managing,
what do you want to be in the cache versus
what do you want to always be streamed directly
from S3.
But by default, files smaller than 128 kilobytes
are cached.
And yeah, if you need to change that,
you can do it.
And you should benchmark your use cases to see
if that actually improves performance or even
changes your cost trade-off.
We'll talk more about costs in a second.
Now, EFS is used under the hood to provide the
caching layer.
So you can, like your mental model could be like
it's going from S3 to EFS and then from EFS
to the compute level if you are using this
caching mechanism.
Otherwise, it's just streamed directly from S3.
And this is probably why you can see that this
storage is available for Lambda as well,
because as you know, EFS is also something you
can use with Lambda.
So in general, everywhere where you can use EFS,
it's very easy to see why they made S3 files
available.
Now, with all of that being said,
how do we get started?
Eoin Shanaghy: Yeah, the ingredients list for this is not too
long, actually.
So you need an S3 bucket, if that wasn't already
obvious.
And then your next thing you'll create is the S3
files file system.
This is a resource that's linked to your bucket
and a file system IAM role.
And you can either link it with a specific
prefix in your bucket rather than the whole
bucket.
And then within this file system resource,
you define a couple of rules.
So you've got the expiration rules,
which say how long data hangs around in the
cache.
I think it's 24 hours by default.
But you can set it up to,
oh, I can't remember.
But it's a lot longer than that.
So you can have your expiration rules,
and then you have the import rules.
The import rules allow you to say what the
maximum file size is for cached data.
So that's 128 kilobytes by default,
but you can set it to higher than that if
you like.
And you say whether the data is imported
automatically when a directory is first accessed
or whether the file is first accessed.
So that could be quite useful in that if you
access one file, S3 files can go ahead and
import everything else in the directory within
the size threshold, if you like.
And these rules can be, these import rules can
be different for different folders.
It's worth mentioning that the IAM policy or the
file system policy we mentioned, it needs to
trust elastic filesystem.amazonaws.com.
So that'll give you a
Luciano Mammino: hint about
Eoin Shanaghy: how tightly integrated it is with EFS,
but it also needs EventBridge and S3 access.
So S3 files uses EventBridge under the hood for
S3 notifications.
The next thing you need is a mount target.
And this is the network link between your S3
files and the subnets in your VPC.
You need one of these for each availability zone
you want to support.
So you'll provide for each of these mount
targets a subnet, security groups,
and then say whether you want to support IPv4 or
v6.
And last thing, you can also create an access
point.
If you don't do this, you just mount the file
system itself, but access points allow you to
provide specific directories as the root and
provide specific POSIX user UID and group ID.
So mount targets and access points look exactly
like the same things you have in EFS,
They have the same name.
The file system resource is quite similar too.
But instead of configuring the EFS performance
and throughput options, which you don't have
here, you just link to your bucket and set the
import and expiration rules.
And as I mentioned, since this is EFS,
it's a service that you have to access over the
VPC.
There's no public endpoint like you have with
normal S3 access.
For Lambda users, that means your function
should be set up with security groups and
subnets.
And when it comes to mounting your file system,
it's just like EFS.
In Lambda, you provide the file system or the
access point ARN and the mount path.
And for EFS, you'll create a volume,
a container volume from the file system or the
access point.
And those volumes are then mount points in your
ECS task definitions.
Because it uses S3, we talked about how it'll
stream directly from S3 for large files.
You need to have either internet access from
your subnet or VPC endpoints to S3.
And your security groups, because it uses NFS,
will need the NFS port outbound.
That's 2049.
I think all in all, if you're used to AWS,
it's a relatively simple one.
It's not the most complex AWS service setup
we've seen.
And it's familiar, right?
It follows EFS very closely.
There are some more things you can configure,
like file system policies, resource policies,
to get tighter access control.
So I think that's probably all we can say about
what S3 Files is, how to set it up.
So let's talk about how it behaves,
maybe starting first with performance,
because this is pretty important.
Luciano Mammino: Yeah, I'm going to read straight from the AWS
documentation just to be sure I give you the
right numbers.
And basically, each file system supports up to
five gigabytes per second of write throughput
performance.
And they say multiple terabytes per second of
aggregated read throughput, up to 250k of read
IOPS performance and 50k of write IOPS
performance.
The maximum per client read throughput is 3
gigabytes per second.
And when accessing files that aren't cached in
your file system, the file system needs to first
retrieve the data from the S3 bucket,
which has latencies in the tens of milliseconds.
Data stored in the file system is read with low
sub-millisecond latencies.
Writes are staged on the file system with
single-digit millisecond latencies.
So that's all that AWS has to say about
performance.
My personal experience is that it might be a
little bit tricky to put all these figures
together
depending on the way you use S3 files,
depending on the shape of your data in S3.
Like you have big files, large files.
How much do you access all of them?
How are you setting up the caching layer?
So in reality, these numbers, I would treat them
just as rough guidance, just to have a
high-level understanding.
But I would recommend people to do your own
benchmarks and see, does it really work for your
use cases?
So that I think moves us into our experience.
Eoin, do you want to share anything about that?
Eoin Shanaghy: Yeah, the nice thing I think there is that
compared to just normal EFS, EFS can be a bit
complex because it's got these different modes.
The latest one is elastic throughput and then
you've got IOPS, right?
You've got provisioned IOPS versus burst,
the old burst method.
can be difficult to get a handle.
And if you do provision IOPS, it can be very
expensive.
So what we wanted to do was just do a
bit of benchmarking.
So we'd have a better idea of when to use
this in our projects as well, when the sweet
spot was, but also to share with everyone.
So we wrote a fairly simple benchmarking
application.
It's not totally scientific because there's
always other influencing factors here.
We tried to make it as simple as possible.
And the approach was we wanted to do reads and
writes of small and large files to S3.
So not that large, but just above the threshold
where they would be cached.
and just measure the performance.
And we also wanted to compare it against all the
different EFS configurations you can have,
and then run it on Lambda and Fargate.
But also, not just Lambda and Fargate,
we wanted to do different CPU and memory
configurations.
So we chose a few different configuration sizes
between 256 megs of memory and 10 gigs of memory
in both Lambda and Fargate.
Now, the repo and results summary will be up on
GitHub if you want to see it for yourself,
and the link will be in the description.
The SAM CloudFormation template we created might
also be useful just if you're figuring out how
do you write one of these things and get it
running yourself with S3 Files.
I think we both had a few cases of trial
and error trying to get the first one working,
so we have something that now works.
So what are our overall findings?
Well, small file writes are generally slightly
faster than S3 put object by about 10 to 20%.
That's what we can see.
The reads are generally dramatically faster than
S3 directly, which you would expect for cached
data, like 5x to 10x faster.
The large file reads are generally much,
much faster with S3 files compared to EFS
options.
And that's because we know it's going through to
streaming directly from S3.
It's still a bit of a surprise to us.
We would have thought that those large file
accesses through the different EFS options,
especially with provisioned IOPS would be
faster, but this is what our results are
showing.
So it's interesting, maybe there's some smart
like parallel fetching going on there in the
background.
In terms of large file writes, there's very
little difference.
It's consistent across the board.
Otherwise, I would say the performance of S3
files is quite similar to EFS with a tiny extra
bit of latency for S3 files.
So unless the only case where S3 files is
significantly faster is in the read operations.
Now, since we tested with various memory and CPU
configurations, it's worth calling out a general
observation, which isn't specific to S3 files.
If you have Fargate or Lambda with 512 megabytes
or less, the network bandwidth really hurts.
And IO can be 10 times worse than just with
2 gigabytes of RAM.
The best performance always came from having 10
gigabytes of RAM.
For Lambda, we know that memory allocation and
network allocation is directly proportion.
Sorry.
For Lambda, we know that memory allocation is
proportionally tied to CPU and network.
And it seems like there's a similar correlation
for Fargate 2.
So if you're doing anything that's IO sensitive,
having a memory allocation of two gigabytes or
more, if possible, will really help you.
The results just start to fall off a cliff if
you try to be really frugal when it comes to
allocating those resources.
There's lots of benefits here, and your mileage
will vary depending on your workload.
But in general, I am saying this is not one
of those services where I'm saying it has a very
narrow niche.
I think it has a broad set of use cases.
If you've got a lot of hot data where
everything's hitting the cache, maybe it's not
going to work very well for you.
But in a normal case, where most of the data
you don't access most of the time,
but you can benefit from some speed up,
especially with small files, and you like the
file system model, then I think it's a real
winner.
Right.
After that, what's the downside?
Luciano Mammino: Yeah, there are quite a few and it's well worth
being aware of them before just jumping straight
into using S3 files for everything.
So the first one we already mentioned to some
extent is that this supports NFS only,
so it doesn't support other network file share
systems or protocols like SMB.
The file system behavior, as we said,
it's trying to do the best that it can possibly
do to fill the gap between what S3 can do
and what a regular file system is supposed to
do.
So there are, of course, things that are missing
or that cannot easily be replicated.
For example, there is no hard links,
there is no atomic renames.
An interesting thing is that if you try,
for instance, to modify a file from the file
system, these changes are staged in the file
system and then eventually they are synchronized
to S3.
which is kind of an interesting optimization,
but comes with some potentially unexpected side
effects that we'll explain in a second.
But the idea is that basically you might be
writing into a few different operations,
files in the local file system.
Maybe the common example is you are appending,
for example, a few times in a few different,
I don't know, seconds.
You wouldn't want, especially if this is a large
file, you wouldn't want that every time you are
doing a change, it immediately tries to
synchronize back to S3.
Because if it's a large file, you are doing a
lot of unnecessary write into S3.
So effectively what S3 files is doing for you,
they are waiting for a certain amount of time to
see, are you doing any other write into this
object before it's actually synchronized back
into one atomic operation into S3.
So the issue here is that you need to be
aware that there is a delay that comes from this
optimization.
So if you are using a mix of access pattern,
for example, if you are reading from the file
system in one place, also writing from the file
system, but then also reading directly from S3
somewhere else, you might see that there is a
little bit of eventual consistency.
So you might not see the new data as soon
as you might expect.
So just be aware of that.
I think the default is 60 seconds.
I'm not even sure if it's something you can
configure.
But yeah, be aware that the consistency isn't
immediate.
So be aware for eventual consistency.
Yeah.
Eoin Shanaghy: And this 60 second wait, if you've got it,
this is a period where it will wait to see
if there are more write operations.
So if you do have another write operation in
that 60 second period, the 60 seconds will
restart.
So it can take multiple minutes before the file
is actually write in that case.
Luciano Mammino: Yeah, I can imagine that one of the use cases
that I don't know if you are kind of streaming
logs from somewhere and then piping them to the
file system itself.
And these logs are basically streaming for the
entire duration of the application,
you're never going to see that file or those
changes at least being reflected into
the S3 packet itself.
So just be aware that some of these use cases,
you need to really understand the model to see
if everything is going to work for you using the
synchronization primitives that S3 Files
provides for you.
And another thing that I actually bumped myself
in one of the projects we are working with one
of our customers,
is that if you use S3 files and you have
an organization with multiple accounts and maybe
you have a control plan account where you have a
kind of a bucket with data you want to share
with a bunch of other accounts,
You would expect that you could use S3 Files
with a bucket that exists in another account,
even if it's in the same organization and
region, but that doesn't seem to be the case.
I actually couldn't find an explicit mention
that this is a real limitation in the
documentation, but everything I tried just
didn't work.
And so my conclusion is that this feature is not
supported yet.
I'm hoping that it's somewhere in the roadmap in
AWS, because I think it could be very useful.
And just to make you understand why this could
be useful, I want to share a little bit of
the project we are working on and why we thought
this could be a good idea.
So we are building a SaaS application where
different customers, they will get their own
dedicated accounts.
So they can run some kind of modeling workloads.
in their own isolated accounts.
So effectively, the shape of the account is that
there is a central control plane where we have
all the shared resources.
For instance, all the models that the SaaS will
expose are stored into S3, and they are
organized with specific prefixes.
And then every time we onboard a new tenant,
there is a new account that is created,
added to the organization,
and a tenant is going to have access only to
a subset of these models.
so we also need to put in place a mechanism
to basically allow each tenant to read only the
models that they have access to from this kind
of golden bucket that exists in the shared
control plane.
So we thought that S3 Files with the feature
that allows you to mount file systems only on
specific parts would be a good match.
Also because these models are kind of immutable,
so we upload them once, they're never changed.
If they are changed, we upload an entire new
version, so we don't even have all the issues we
just described in terms of synchronizing the
data.
We literally just needed to have an EFS mount
from S3, and S3 Files seems to be pretty good
with all the caching mechanisms.
but we don't suffer from all of the eventual
consistency.
So unfortunately, because the cross account
mount doesn't work, what we needed to do in the
end is to figure out a synchronization mechanism
where we can selectively replicate data from the
central bucket in the control plane to a bucket
that exists in each tenant account,
which is a little bit annoying.
It kind of works in the end.
It just adds a bit of extra complexity that we
didn't want to use.
But otherwise, so far, S3 Files has been working
really well.
We don't really have a benchmark for this
specific project where we're going to have a
quite varied mix of big and small files
depending on the model.
So I think maybe later on, if this is something
interesting, we might do another episode with
the details once we start to use it.
with more and more customers and get some more
realistic data.
But yeah, so far, just now, you cannot do
cross-account mounts, but otherwise,
S3 Files has been working really well for this
project.
So there is one more caveat that I think is
worth mentioning, is that if you rename and move
files a lot, that can affect performance.
And if you have a prefix with millions of
objects, and you've just tried to rename that
prefix,
like just renaming the top folder,
for example, in the file system, that could take
hours.
So there's just something to be aware.
And I think there is also some kind of
limitation, right, on like AWS will warn you
that that might happen and you need to accept
the warning explicitly.
Eoin Shanaghy: Yeah.
If you've, it will actually look at how many
objects are in your bucket before you create a
file system.
And if you've got like, the documentation says
if you've got something like 12 million objects,
Luciano Mammino: that
Eoin Shanaghy: means there's a potential for a four hour rename
operation.
And it'll give you an error unless you accept a
warning saying, you know, it's okay,
I'm willing to accept the risk and avoid it.
Luciano Mammino: So, this is technically something that might
fail at deployment if you accidentally...
Eoin Shanaghy: Unless you add an explicit accept warning
property
Luciano Mammino: to
Eoin Shanaghy: your configuration.
Luciano Mammino: Okay.
So, hopefully that gives you an idea of some of
the trade-offs and the limitations and missing
features.
So, you are a little bit more informed when you
decide to use S3 files for your projects,
but I think we need to talk about cost.
So, what's the story there?
Eoin Shanaghy: OK, well, you've got the S3 pricing.
You're always going to pay for that under the
hood.
Then on top of that, data stored in your cache
is priced at around 30 cents per gigabyte or
more, depending on the region.
What's the story with Sao Paulo?
It's like 57 cents compared to 30 cents in US
East 1.
I don't know.
Brazilian listeners, please tell us how you feel
about this and what you do about it.
Reads from the cache are around $0.03 per
gigabyte.
Again, that starts at that price.
That's reads from a cache, right?
$0.03 per gigabyte.
And file writes are around $0.06 or more per
gigabyte, 6 cents or 7 cents per gigabyte.
Now, if you're familiar with EFS elastic
throughput pricing, you might notice that those
prices are the exact same.
The main difference is that files that aren't in
your cache are read from S3 with no additional
cost.
So that's the way to think about it.
There is an additional cost here, but compared
to EFS, there's a huge saving for reads that
don't hit your cache.
So in practice this means you can save a lot
of money compared to EFS but there is a premium
compared to just using S3.
In exchange for that you get fast read and write
performance especially on cached small files.
If all or most of your data is small and
frequently accessed it can end up all in the
cache so the costs can mount up and maybe it
doesn't make sense there.
On the other hand, if most data is larger or
less frequently accessed, you might have the
sweet spot for S3 files.
One thing we didn't mention yet is that this
will also work with all the different access
tiers in S3, like infrequently accessed,
and Glacier, and everything.
So you can still get those cost savings in your
S3 layer.
And yeah, otherwise, there are those trade-offs.
You talked about Luciano, particularly the big
one, which is this 60-second write-back delay.
Luciano Mammino: OK, so let's try to wrap this episode up.
I'm going to try to do a quick recap first
and then give you our final take.
So S3 is amazing.
We all use it in all kinds of use cases.
But the reality is that it's not a file system.
So there are still use cases where applications
are expected to have a file system.
So you need to bridge the gap somehow.
And S3 Files is a new way to do that.
And it is pretty promising.
it basically lets you mount S3-backed storage
into EC2, ECS, EKS, and even Lambda using EFS
concepts that you might have seen already if you
used EFS as a service.
And this is not strange when you realize that
under the hood, AWS is using EFS as a caching
layer between reading from S3 directly and
making that data available as a file system into
EC2, ECS, EKS, or whatever.
So that's why you can see a lot of EFS
things.
And it might be very familiar if you have used
EFS.
I think that the interesting story there is that
you can keep S3 as the source of truth,
but give the application a more traditional
system interface when they need it.
And you can also leverage this caching layer for
improving performance whenever you,
for instance, are reading lots of small files.
And also if you were using EFS before,
there is a potential here to save money because
you are not always reading from EFS,
you are not always keeping all the data into
EFS, which is generally where most of the cost
would come from if you use EFS with lots of
big files, for example.
So our benchmark suggests that S3 files can be
quite interesting for workloads where you're
doing lots of small file reads, and effectively,
in those cases, if you would read directly from
S3, that might impact performance.
But again, if you're only reading small files
and they all end up in the cache,
maybe the cost is going to be quite high and
as comparable as just having the files directly
in EFS.
So just be aware of that.
I think it's still having a kind of a good
mix of file sizes.
It's probably the sweet spot when you need to
use S3 files.
Now, our take is that, with all of that being
said, you still need to be aware that this is
not magically turning an S3 bucket into a fully
fledged file system.
You should still understand what are the
trade-offs, what are the limitations,
and it is still kind of a middle ground.
It is very practical, but just be aware and look
carefully what your application is trying to do
with the file system and make sure it's not
trying to do things that are not supported.
And again, the other thing to be aware is be
careful about mixed access patterns.
So if you are using that bucket for S3 files,
but also using that bucket directly,
accessing it for read and writes, there might be
synchronization issues.
So make sure you truly understand that
synchronization model.
Make sure you understand that 60-second
write-back limitation we discussed before.
And with all of that into the picture,
make sure your design still makes sense.
So if you are building a complex architecture,
just put everything in the picture before just
saying that S3 file doesn't work for you,
because it might work if you are under the right
circumstances.
So now, as always, and especially now because
this is such a new service, we have used it
only for some experiments and into a project
that is still very early,
So this is just our early opinions and our early
findings on this service.
So we'd be really curious to hear,
have you used it?
What did you find?
And have you used something else that maybe you
think is going to work better for you and why?
Just let us know what are your experiences,
what is your opinion, if you think something is
missing, because we are always learning from our
listeners, and we're always eager to hear your
stories.
And that brings us to the end of this episode.
But before saying goodbye, we'll have to thank
you, our sponsor, fourtheorem, for powering yet
another episode of AWS Bites Podcast.
And fourtheorem can help you if you're trying to
design reliable, cost-effective storage
architecture on AWS,
especially if you're using S3, EFS,
and now S3 files, or if you're building all
kinds of serverless workloads with Lambda,
containers, and any other thing like that.
So just check out fourtheorem.com to find out
more about what we do and some of our case
studies.
Thank you very much, and we'll see you in the
next episode.